MAGGIE BAKER / Web Developer in Denver, CO

919.218.6875 / maggiedbaker@gmail.com

I am passionate about creating technology that improves peoples' lives. I love disruptive ideas and intelligent design. I am an autonomous learner and a dedicated teammate. My strongest technology skills are JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS & SCSS, PHP (Laravel) and Ruby on Rails.

Recent Work

SHIFT / shift.healthecareers.com

Web application that matches traveling nurses with potential employers. Built with the LAMP stack using Laravel and Backbone.js, jQuery and SCSS on the front end. My roles in this project have included database migrations, CRUD capabilities for the admin panel, CSV exporting functionality, authentication and security features, hooking up automated email notifications for users, and plenty of front-end JavaScript and styling.

PORTABLE X-RAY IMAGING TOOL / NDA protected

Imaging tool distributed to bomb squads for storing and manipulating images associated with suspicious activity. Users can log in to CRUD "incidents", upload images, and then use a Photoshop-like interface to adjust each image for a closer look. I worked with one other developer on the front-end of this app, mostly in vanilla JavaScript, and my main role was building the histogram window and level sliders that adjust the image's tones in the editing interface. I also built and styled most of the CRUD and login interfaces using HTML and CSS.

CONSTRUCTION E-COMMERCE SITE / NDA protected

E-commerce site for manufacturers to search for, bundle and purchase parts for construction equipment, with helpful guides to make sure they're buying the right combination of items. I wrote modular HTML served up in PHP files, SCSS and JavaScript to build the user interface of this application, including the cart, global navigation, checkout page and the users' 'bundle' list pages.

Employment

Application Developer / SPIRE DIGITAL

Denver, CO: Mar 2016 - present

I work in small, agile teams to build scalable web applications in a variety of languages and frameworks. During my time at Spire, I have contributed to more than 10 applications, and my tasks have included both front and back-end work, with an emphasis on JavaScript. I work closely on a daily basis with designers, project managers, product owners, QA and clients.

Strategist / MADE MOVEMENT

Boulder, CO: Oct 2013 - Jun 2015

Led the development and implementation of Made's proprietary 'Learn, Plan, Make' cycle, which optimizes technology on a quarterly basis through web analytics. Conducted marketing research and wrote strategic briefs for creative teams that resulted in campaigns for Etsy, Seventh Generation, TGI Fridays, vegas.com, Copper Mountain and the Honest Kitchen.

E-commerce Community Manager / MADE MOVEMENT

Boulder, CO: Sep 2012 - Oct 2013

Spearheaded social media campaigns for Made's all American-made e-commerce site, MadeCollection.com, helping to grow the site's Facebook page from 5k to 10k followers in its first months of existence. Delivered weekly web analytics reports to internal teams, designed email campaigns, coordinated vendors and wrote product descriptions for the site.

Artist Manager / MISSY MCLAMB INC, CAROL ANN WACHTER &

KIMBERLY DEMMY DESIGN

Jun 2010 - Jan 2013, Chapel Hill, NC, and Boulder, CO

Managed all finances, projects, client communication and post-shoot production for the documentary photography studio Missy McLamb, Inc. Used Adobe Illustrator, Lightroom and Photoshop daily. Also freelanced as an administrative, financial and creative assistant for fashion designer & artist Carol Ann Wachter, and modern interior designer Kimberly Demmy.

Dev Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript, PHP, Ruby

Front End Development

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, jQuery, Handlebars

Front End Frameworks

Bootstrap 3, Backbone.js, some experience with Vue.js and AngularJS, currently studying React.js

Back End Frameworks

Laravel, LoopBack, Rails

Database

SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ActiveRecord

Tools

Grunt, Gulp, NPM, Bower, Git

Methodologies

Agile, RESTful design, MVC, Object-oriented design

Education

Dev Bootcamp

July - Nov 2015 Attended 19-week immersive coding school in New York City

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Aug 2007 - May 2010 B.A. Journalism and Mass Communication. Graduated with highest honors

Clark University

Aug 2006 - May 2007 Attended on the Strassler Scholarship for the fine arts

Hobbies

Banjo study

Clawhammer and three-finger style. Performed weekly with a bluegrass band between 2012 and 2015 in Boulder, CO, and currently taking weekly lessons in Denver, CO.